How did you come to do
the aid work for Indian children?
I am deeply moved by your teaching.
How did you decide to
help the children in India?
There must be lots of poor
people in our country also.
I would like to know
why you chose to work in India.
Inside our county, we see the poor
and rich only within our country.
But if you look beyond our country,
there are rich and poor people
in other countries.
So, if you compare our country
with another country,
the rich people there are
poorer than our poor people.
Let's say we divide our people into
three levels: high, middle, and low class.
And what happens when we divide
the other country's people
into the same three groups.
We belong in the high class of the three.
The poor people in India belong
to the low class of the three.
That means our low class is better off
than the high class over there.
So, within our country, it is good to
help those in the low class.
But I have seen the other country.
Our poor people live
better than their rich people.
So, I thought it would be good to
help the poorest of the their poor.
So, I do the work of helping
the poorest people in the poorest country.
Our country's poor people belong to
the poor among the rich countries.
So, there are rich countries,
average countries, and poor countries.
Our poor people belong to
the poors of a rich country.
The poor people I help abroad
belong to the poor countries.
Though we use the same word poor,
the meaning can be world apart.
Our poors are poor among the rich.
The poors over there are among the poor.
There is a huge gap.
So, I help children
in the third world countries.
Why don't I help adults?
I do help some, but I am unable to
help both adults as well as children.
We have no choice but to look
the other way when we see them dying.
Why?
Because we do not have the capability.
The children will suffer
for the next 10,20, 30 years,
if we don't educate them or
leave them malnourished.
But an adult will die after about
a year of hardship. That will be the end.
Of course, they should be helped,
but the children must come first.
In our country, even the poor people
can get some food, right?
Someone with no food. But if he makes
an effort, he will be able to eat.
He can even beg for food.
Nobody will deny him food when he asks.
But in that poor country,
they can't even beg for food.
There is no food to beg for.
In North Korea, there is no food
to be begged for. Period.
No household has any food;
they live on wildgrass porridge.
So, I am not concerned
about our country.
Our government uses tax to provide help
for the poor through social programs.
It is the responsibility of
our government.
But the governments in poor countries
don't take that responsibility.
In our country, neighbors help
and care for such poor people.
But there, everyone one is
poor so no one is able to help.
In our country, even through tough times,
our parents or our relatives can help.
There, the parents and the relatives are
all poor so the children can't be care for.
I am not from that country,
it is not my country,
neither am I their neighbor,
nor am I their parent.
I have nothing to do with them
as far as the responsibility goes.
But those who are responsible
don't have the capability to help.
Or even if they do, they will not help.
So, even though they are not
my countrymen, not Buddhists,
not my neighbors, not my relatives,
and not my children,
since I am born a human being,
as a human being,
I can't help but take care of them.
I care for the Muslim children
who defaced the Buddha statue.
I care for the children of the North
Koreans who once invaded us.
Regardless of their ideology,
religion, race, or past grievances.
Why? The starving children are not
responsible for their own state
That is how I came to help those children.
Travelling around India, I could see that
parents give births to their children,
but could not do anything else.
Not because they chose not to, but they
had no ability to do anything for them.
They only think that one less mouth
to feed if one of them is taken away.
Long ago when we didn't have enough
to eat, know what they used to say.
They'd say,
"Go get work to feed yourself!"
They used to tell teenage kids
to earn to feed themselves.
How can a grown up not
be able to feed oneself?
This is how we came to
help those children.
Not just a few but every child
can't attend school.
Not just a few but everyone
in the village can't read.
in the village is starving.
Not just a few but every sick person
can't get medical care.
Everyone in the village can't get
medical care. There are places like these.
How can there be such a place?
Come with me on the pilgrimage
and see for yourself.
Go and see the village
where I built a school.
Real destitution exists there.
They have no clothes.
They wear something like a rag.
A closet?
No such thing.
What they're wearing is all they have.
They have no other clothing to speak of.
No house to speak of.
Maybe one pot for cooking utensil.
No silverware. Why?
They eat with their fingers.
They don't have any side dishes.
We don't feed separate
side dishes to dogs, do we?
Whatever gets poured into
a bowl is what they eat to live.
So, how can they think about
education in such state?
Since I am a monk, I don't tell you
to make a lot of money, do I?
I don't.
So, why am I involved in their lives?
But human beings, at the very least,
should not die of hunger, no?
They die from mild diseases.
In our country, too, people died of
tuberculosis 40-50 years ago, right?
In those days, people died of smallpox,
and other diseases.
But these days, people do
not dies of such diseases.
People used to die of cholera,
dysentery. Kids dies of measles.
But these days, no one
dies of these diseases.
So, we've got to help those poor people.
If I were to help all the
poor people in our country,
I should have become a
philanthropist, not a monk.
A monk gives up all possessions
and is to live as a pauper.
But when people are dying around you,
though Buddhist practice is important,
what sort of practice is it
ignoring such people's plight?
So, as a Buddhist only praying
to Buddha every day
for good blessings without
doing my duty to help others,
doesn't fit the teachings
and the law of Causation.
And if someone up there were to look down
wouldn't I be despised?
How can I get good fortunes and blessings?
I should be worthy of good blessings, no?
So, for the most destitute on earth, those
men who work for less than a dollar a day,
if we donate $1 a day,
we can help those people.
That is how it got started.
My heart ached as I traveled around India.
And I thought about Buddha.
You have heard of the four sightings
at four gates in his life story, right?
He saw an old man outside the east gate,
saw a sick man outside the south gate.
He saw a dead man outside the north gate.
They weren't there by happenstance.
An old man who had no help. In those days,
the old slaves were just abandoned.
A sick man who didn't get medical care.
At the time, a sick slaves were abandoned.
Without a proper burial,
dead slaves were just thrown away
in the corpse pile in the forest.
Buddha could not help but
agonize over what life was about.
As we travel around India,
we could not help but agonize
over what life was really about.
We needed to reflect upon
what we were doing.
First, we felt sorry for them.
Second, it gave us the opportunity to
truly review what life was all about.
We needed to review our personal views
and refect upon what the Truth was.
We had to look deeply into our lives.
So, I actually rediscovered Buddha
during my travels in India.
My thought of the great
Buddha who helped me
when I prayed to him has been transformed.
I came to see a Great Sage who felt
the pain of suffering people
in his heart and cared for them.
So, even though I can't
do all that he could,
I would try to do my small part at least.
I thought about what Buddha would do
if he were to appear here to us now.